MUTHUKAMATCHI MANICKAM

QA AUTOMATION ENGINEER (Belgium Long Stay D Visa)

kamu@belyf.com | +32-494-80-87-16 | https://linkedin.com/in/kamu-m



SUMMARY

An insightful, passion-driven IT professional with around 7 years of extensive experience in the software development lifecycle, including designing, developing, and implementing comprehensive test plans, test suites, and test processes. Proven track record in identifying critical bugs, achieving user acceptance, and enhancing software reliability.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Reduced testing time by 50% by implementing advanced automated testing frameworks.
- Mentored and trained over 5 junior engineers, improving team skills and efficiency.
- Followed bug tracking processes, resolving critical bugs and enhancing software reliability.
- Improved application performance by 30% through comprehensive performance testing.
- Enhanced test coverage by 25% by developing and implementing new testing processes.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

Automation Testing, CI/CD Implementation, Performance Testing, Load Testing, Database Testing, API Testing, Agile Methodologies, Version Control (Git), Test Framework Development, Mentorship & Training, Cross-Functional Collaboration, Process Improvement, Software Quality Assurance, Test Plan Development

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Robotframework, Python, Java, VB Script, Selenium, TestSigma, TestNG, Locust, Jenkins, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Git, JIRA, UFT, Chai, Mocha, Gherkin/Cucumber, HP ALM, SoapUI, TestRail

WORK EXPERIENCE

Aspire Systems.

Test Lead

Chennai, India

Jan 2022 – Present

Client: Lendkey (https://www.lendkey.com/)

- Technologies include Robotframework, Python, TestSigma, Locust, Git.
- Developed robot scripts from scratch for two projects (Verify and Ocrolus) and set up a Jenkins CI/CD pipeline.
- Contributed significantly to critical projects, earning client appreciation.
- Implemented load testing scripts in Locust for the Verify project.
- Conducted a successful PoC in Testsigma and applied it to the Aliro project.

Cognizant Technology Solutions.

Chennai, India

Associate

Jun 2018 – Jan 2022

Client: Opsec Security Group (https://www.opsecsecurity.com/)

- · Technologies include Java, Selenium, TestNG, Mongo, Git
- Automated test cases and developed Keyword and Data-driven frameworks using Selenium WebDriver and TestNG.
- Wrote Mongo and Elastic Queries for testing and used Git for version control.
- Tested REST APIs and web applications, maintaining stories, test plans, and execution cycles in JIRA.

Client: The Travellers Companies, Inc (https://www.travelers.com/)

- Technologies include UFT, VB Script, Chai, Mocha, HP ALM, Soap
- Automated tests using an in-house framework (Travtest), and designed E2E Automation Scripts.
- Performed functional and regression testing, created test plans and conditions.
- Participated in organizational activities like goal tracking, seminars, and coding games.

OrchestrateHR Solutions Private Limited.

Madurai, India

Application Developer

Aug 2017 - May 2018

- Technologies include ASP.Net, VB Script, SQL, Telerik Grid, Telerik Report Designer.
- Designed various forms and web pages.

CERTIFICATIONS / TRAINING

- Automation Anywhere Certified Advanced RPA professional.
- Udemy courses on Python, Chai, Mocha, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Cucumber
- Java Backend Development track in Jetbrains (https://hyperskill.org/tracks/12)

EDUCATION

B Tech (IT) — K.L.N. College of IT, Sivagangai. (CGPA 8.3)